Guide to the Mattie E. Hewitt & Richard A. Smith Photograph Collection 1919-1961 (bulk 1920-1939) PR 26
New-York Historical Society
Mattie E. Hewitt & Richard A. Smith photograph collection
1919-1961 (bulk 1920-1939)
New-York Historical Society
PR 26
11.89 Linear feet (Approx. 5,000 black and white photographic prints, 8 x 10 inches or smaller. 400 8 x 10 inch black and white film negatives)
The collection contains photographic prints and negatives by noted garden and architecture photographer Mattie Edwards Hewitt and her nephew, Richard Averill Smith. The bulk of the clients are popular magazines and interior decorators. Views of fashionable apartment interiors, newly built houses, small urban gardens, and other residential settings display the work of decorators and the tastes of well-known people. There are also interiors of hotels, restaurants, clubs, shops, and decorator exhibitions.
Provenance
Gift from the Nassau County Museum in 1971; additional donated received in 2013.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to 30 photocopies per day per person. Suitability of the original for photocopying is at the discretion of the staff. Neither blueprints nor tracings can be copied under any circumstances. Duplication of large-format items will be done by the house photographer. See Print Room guidelines for details.
Biographical Note
Mattie Edwards Hewitt (d. 1956)
Richard Averill Smith (1897-1971)
Although Mattie Edwards Hewitt's photographs stand as a remarkable visual record of nearly four decades of architecture and design, little is known about her personal history. Born in Saint Louis, she grew up in a middle-class family and studied art until her marriage to the photographer Arthur Hewitt. Her husband taught her the basic techniques for processing and printing film, and she developed her craft working as his assistant.
In 1901, Hewitt traveled to the Pan American Exposition in Buffalo, New York, where she met Frances Benjamin Johnston, a successful photographer from Washington D.C. who would have a significant influence on her life and work. After their initial meeting, Hewitt and Johnston wrote to one another frequently, developing personal as well as professional ties. Johnston began to send Hewitt the film from her commissions around the country. Eventually, Hewitt was processing and printing most of Johnston's assignments, billing clients and managing her accounts. During these years in Saint Louis, as Hewitt assisted both her husband and Johnston, she longed to spend less of her time in the darkroom and more behind the camera. Hewitt divorced her husband in 1909 and moved with Johnston to New York City.
The two women embarked as partners, seizing the opportunity presented by a wave of public building in New York to establish themselves as architectural photographers. They photographed the new Public Library, Hotel Manhattan, the Cathedral of St. John the Divine, West Point Academy and the New Theatre. Their growing reputation gained them commissions with many of the leading architects of the day including McKim, Mead and White, C. Grant LaFarge, Cass Gilbert, and Cram, Goodhue and Ferguson. The images they made during these years bear the credit "Miss Johnston and Mrs. Hewitt" or "Frances Benjamin Johnston and Mattie Edwards Hewitt." Despite their successes, the partnership ended in a bitter conflict in 1917, leaving both Hewitt and Johnston to pursue independent careers.
Relying on the reputation and client-base she had developed with Johnston, Hewitt established a business of her own. She specialized in photography for designers, architects, and landscape architects, documenting domestic and commercial interiors, and gardens. Hewitt's professional development coincided with an era of great activity in interior and garden architecture. Increasing interest in these fields gave rise to a proliferation of magazines and illustrated books that required high quality photographs. Hewitt's images were well regarded by both designers and editors in pursuit of new and dynamic sites to portray for their subscribers. Many periodicals published her photographs, including House and Garden, Town and Country, House Beautiful, The Delineator, Home and Field, and Architecture Magazine. Her work also appeared regularly in the New York Times, the Herald Tribune, the New York Evening Post, The World, and the New York Evening Sun.
Hewitt kept files on all of her assignments that included notes and extra prints that she could offer to publishers when the opportunity arose. She would sometimes suggest an article on an estate or garden for which she could supply the images. She pursued new commissions consistently and traveled frequently, with her heavy wooden view cameras, tripods, and lenses in tow. Although she worked with an assistant or hired a boy to help with the equipment when her budget permitted, the work was demanding. When landscape and garden assignments were scarce during the winter months, she would occasionally freelance at banquets at the large hotels in New York. At these events, she photographed early in the evening, made prints in a hotel room fitted with a makeshift darkroom and sold them to the banquet guests as they left the party. Her skill and persistence carried her through over thirty years as a professional photographer.
Most of Hewitt's significant work was made during the twenties and thirties, although she continued to photograph almost until the end of her life. Although she was appreciated in her professional circle for her fine sensibility and technique, she never found recognition beyond the realm of commercial photography. She died in Boston in 1956.
When Mattie Edwards Hewitt retired, she gave her print files to Richard Averill Smith. As a young man, Smith had worked for Hewitt (his wife's aunt) before becoming a commercial photographer himself. He opened his first studio in New York City in 1928 and came to specialize in photographing hotels, restaurants, and private homes. Smith moved his studio to Flushing and then, around 1955, to Levittown, New York. He was recognized for the outstanding quality of his work and received numerous awards including the designation of Master Photographer from the National Photographers Association (NPA). He lectured nationally in conjunction with the NPA and taught photography in Farmingdale, New York. He died in Levittown in 1971.
Scope and Content Note
The Mattie E. Hewitt & Richard A. Smith Photographic Collection contains approximately 5000 photographic prints and 400 negatives made by these architectural photographers between 1910 and 1960, with the bulk of the images produced during the 1920s and 1930s. The core of the collection consists of a running file of prints kept by Mattie Edwards Hewitt. When she retired, she gave this file to her nephew, Richard Averill Smith, who was also a commercial photographer. Smith added some of his own images to the file. After his death in 1971, The Nassau County Museum acquired the collection, which consisted of some 12,000 images, and distributed portions of it to various institutions according their geographic interests. The New-York Historical Society received material from approximately 500 assignments, many of them residences in Manhattan. Approximately three-quarters of the images are made by Hewitt, and the remainder by Smith. The work of the two photographers is filed together and is arranged into two series: Photographic Prints; and Negatives.
Both series are arranged alphabetically by assignment, which is typically the name of the business or homeowner. Many of these photographs were taken for a specific interior decorator or architect but they are only filed under the decorator's name where the owner's name is unknown. A database was established with cross-references to the decorator; a list of assignments organized by designer follows this container list. Correct corporate names were established when possible. If not, files were left under the designation originally assigned by Hewitt or Smith. Establishing accurate hotel names proved difficult. Vanderbilt Hotel, for example, was listed in period phone directories as both "Vanderbilt Hotel" and "Hotel Vanderbilt." If looking for a specific hotel, the researcher is advised to look in both potential places.
Some background information is available in the collection file.
Arrangement
The work of the two photographers is filed together. Both series are arranged alphabetically by assignment title, which is typically the name of the business or homeowner.
Note that boxes 35 to 42 contain photographs and negatives from the additional donation made in 2013. The folders in these boxes have been inserted alphabetically in the finding aid by the name of business of homeowner, so box numbers sometimes skip around.
The collection is organized into the following series:
Missing Title
Series I: Photographic Prints
Series II: Negatives
Apartment houses.; Architect-designed houses -- New York (State) -- New York.; Architecture -- New York (State) -- New York.; Gardens -- New York (State) -- New York.; Hotels -- Decoration -- New York (State) -- New York.; Interior architecture; Photography of interiors; Radio stations -- Decoration; Restaurants -- Decoration -- New York (State) -- New York.; Store decoration; New York (N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; Yachts; negatives (photographs); Photographic prints.; Bourke-White, Margaret, 1904-1971; Hearst, William Randolph, 1863-1951; Loewy, Raymond, 1893-1986; Nadelman, Elie, 1882-1946; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison), 1874-1960; Rockefeller, Percy A.; Smith, Richard Averill; Vanderbilt, William K. (William Kissam), 1878-1944
- Series I: Photographic Prints
  Scope and Contents note
  Series I consists of the images from approximately 500 assignments by Hewitt and Smith. The majority of the prints are credited to one photographer or the other with a stamp on the verso or the photographer's insignia in the print. The images are mostly silver bromide prints made on standard 8x10 inch commercial paper, and many are toned.
  Notes about the assignments made on original file folders accompany the prints and may include the location, decorator or designer, the date photographed, and subsequent dates that prints were made for various publications. Research indicates that the images did not always appear in the periodicals on the dates noted, suggesting that prints were commissioned or submitted but not necessarily published.
  Mattie Hewitt's photographs of New York City residences record both the "machine age" interiors of the first decades of the 20th century and the more classic, historicizing style that eventually eclipsed it. Sometimes referred to as "Forties Style," it originates in the work of several Paris decorators of the late 1930s and involves judicious use of Baroque, Rococo, and other period forms in modern settings. In the Hewitt photographs, the interiors of Elsie De Wolfe, A. A. Rateau, and Serge Roche best epitomize the style. Among Hewitt's more prestigious residential commissions are the homes of theatrical agent Elizabeth Marbury (De Wolfe) at 13 Sutton Place; Ann Morgan (De Wolfe) at 3 Sutton Place; decorator Rose Cumming (Cumming) at 54 East 55th Street; publisher Conde Nast (De Wolfe) at 1040 Park Avenue; banker and collector George Blumenthal (A. A. Rateau) at 50 East 7th Street; and actress Hope Hampton (De Wolfe) at 1145 Park Avenue. Also represented in the collection are furniture and rooms designed by Donald Deskey (Ypsilanti Reed Furniture Company); John Vassos (Studio of Margaret Bourke White); and architects George Howe and William Lescaze (home of Mr. and Mrs. Herbert Dreyfus).
  Hewitt's commercial interiors are well represented. She photographed the numerous hotels, restaurants, and clubs including Ruby Foo Restaurant, Town & Country Restaurant, the St. Regis Hotel, the Gramercy Park Hotel, and the Court House Club in Manhattan. A number of design exhibitions and displays from the twenties and thirties are also pictured, such as the Decorators Club 1928 Exhibition, the National Sculpture Exhibition, the Metal Products Exhibition, and the Old New York Exhibition. Hewitt's excursions into product photography range from the shiny fixtures made by International Nickel Co. to the exotic flowers raised by Hortus International.
  While Hewitt was very a prolific garden and landscape photographer only a small fraction of the images in the collection represent this work. However, there are images of several estates outside the city as well as a handful of terrace and rooftop gardens in Manhattan. There are also some exterior views of particular buildings in New York City, sometimes in conjunction with interior shots.
  Richard Averill Smith's work also includes both residential and commercial interior views. Well-known for his images of hotels and restaurants, Smith photographed Tavern on the Green, and Café Arnold, Hotel Astor and the Vanderbilt Hotel. His domestic interiors from the 30s and 40s record homes and apartments in and around New York City and document a variety of tastes and styles of the era. There are a few assignment files, including Gimbel Brothers and the Waldorf Astoria, that contain work by both Hewitt and Smith.
  The prints are arranged alphabetically by assignment title, which is usually the name of the business or resident of the home photographed. Addresses listed are those shown in the photographs, if known, and are in Manhattan unless otherwise stated. The number of prints varies from assignment to assignment.
  - Allerton House, 1931 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Madison and 55th Street
  - Allerton House, 1942 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    Lexington and 39th Street
  - Allerton House, 1946-1947 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
    Lexington and 57th Street
  - Alovoine, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    Rockefeller Plaza, Fine Arts Exposition
  - Altschul, Frank, 1929 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    550 Park Avenue
  - America's Little House, 1949 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    Park Avenue and 39th Street
  - Ames. Paul R (Offsite-box 35, Folder 730)
    General
    Woodstock, NY
  - Amsterdam, Gary (Offsite-box 35, Folder 731)
    Lake Mahopac, NY
  - Angell, Ernest (Offsite-box 35, Folder 732)
    "Sneeden's Landing" Palisades, NY
  - Annapolis Hotel, 1949 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    1111 H St. NW, Washington, DC
  - Arden Studios, 1931 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - Armory, 258th Field Artillery, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Arts and Decoration, 1931 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ashton, Henry (Offsite-box 35, Folder 733)
    Bronxville, NY
  - Atkins Ltd., 1934 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
    16 West 57th Street
  - Atkins, William, Mrs., 1933 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
    36 East 72nd Street
  - Bache, Jules, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 13)
    8 East 67th Street
  - Bache, L., Mrs., 1928 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
    791 Park Avenue
  - Baker, Cecil F., 1934 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
    433 East 51st Street
  - Baker, Mary (Offsite-box 35, Folder 734)
    Yonkers, NY
  - Ballantine estate, 1929 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16)
    King's Point Road, Great Neck, NY
  - Barclay Hotel, 1945 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
    111 East 48th Street
  - Barker, Alexander Mrs. (Offsite-box 35, Folder 735)
    "Faraway Farm", Cross River, NY
  - Barnard College, 1926 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
    The Deanery
  - Barnes, Albert, Jr., Mrs., 1930 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 19)
    775 Park Avenue
  - Barnes, Martha, 1945 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 20)
    3 East 66th Street
  - Barr, Lockwood (Offsite-box 35, Folder 736)
    Pelham Manor, NY
  - Barratt, Roswell F., 1930 - 1945 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 21)
    10 West 33rd Street
  - Bartholomew, George H., 1938 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 22)
    Huntington, NY
  - Barton, Price & Willson, 1921-1397 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 23)
    46 East 57th Street
  - Baum, Dwight James (Offsite-box 35, Folder 737)
    Riverdale, NY
  - Beaux Arts Apartments, 1930-1944 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 24)
    307 East 44th Street
  - Beebe, William, 1930 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 25)
    33 West 67th Street
  - Bell, Gordon Knox, Mrs., 1925 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 26)
    154 East 66th Street
  - Best & Company, exterior, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 27)
  - Biddle, A.J. Drexel (Offsite-box 35, Folder 738)
    Irvington, NY
  - Blagden, Dexter, Mrs., 1920 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 28)
    41 East 51st Street
  - Blair, James A., Jr., Col., 1927 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 29)
    101 West 57th Street
  - Blind Brook Club, 1919 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 30)
    Port Chester, NY
  - Bliss, Cornelius N., Jr., Mrs., 1924-1928 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 31)
    4 East 66th Street
  - Bliss, Frank Mrs. (Offsite-box 35, Folder 739)
    New Rochelle, NY
  - Bloomingdale, Samuel J., 1928 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 32)
    910 Fifth Avenue
  - Blumenthal, George, 1928 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 33-35)
    150 East 70th Street
    See also: Series II, Box 25, Folder 668
  - B'nai Jeshurun Congregation, 1925 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 36)
    257 West 88th Street
  - Bogardus, Egbert, 1945 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 37)
    Sharon, CT
  - Boomer, Lucius M., 1922 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 38)
    300 Park Avenue
  - Boomer, Lucius M., 1934 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 39)
    Park Avenue and 50th Street, Waldorf Astoria
  - Borden Farm Products Cmpany, 1928 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 40)
    Nesbitt and Orange Streets, Newark, NJ
  - Bossom, Alfred C., 1930 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 41)
    680 Fifth Avenue
  - Bourke-White, Margaret, 1930 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 42)
    Chrysler Building
  - Bowen, E. Cockrane, Mrs., 1932-1935 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 43)
    1010 Fifth Avenue
  - Brady, William G., 1929 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 44)
    Lexington Ave. and 79th Street
  - Braunstein, Abraham, Mrs., 1936 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 45)
    320 Central Park West
  - Breed, F. Nelson and Fuller and Dick, architects, 1929-1932 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 46)
  - Breed, William C., 1934 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 47)
    435 East 52nd Street, River House
  - Brewster, Robert S. (Offsite-box 35, Folder 740)
    "Avalon", Mount Kisco, NY
  - Brinton, Bradford, 1930-1937 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 48)
    1001 Park Avenue
  - Brooks, Frederick, Mrs., 1931 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 49)
    1007 Fifth Avenue
  - Brost, Ray Henderson (Offsite-box 35, Folder 741)
  - Brown, Archibald M., 1931-1937 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 50)
  - Browning, R. R., 1929 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 51)
    Wilmot Road, New Rochelle, NY
  - Brunovan, 1930 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 52)
    383 Madison Avenue
  - Bruyn, William E., Mrs., 1930 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 53)
    784 Park Avenue
  - Bryce, Edith Parker, 1925 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 54)
    32 East 58th Street
  - Bull, E. Myron (Offsite-box 35, Folder 742)
    Toro Hill, Monroe, NY
  - Bull, H. W., 1930 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 55)
    171 East 62nd Street
  - Bull, William R. (Offsite-box 35, Folder 743)
    Pelham, NY
  - Bullock, Hugh, Mrs., 1935 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 56)
    435 East 52nd Street
  - Burroghs, Ambrose Hamment (Offsite-box 35, Folder 744)
    "Woodland"
  - Bush, Joseph (Offsite-box 35, Folder 745)
  - Busk, W. Hamilton (Offsite-box 35, Folder 746)
    Purchase, NY
  - Cadieux Company Florists, 1921-1925 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 57)
    1007 Madison Avenue
  - Café Arnold, 1947 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 58)
    240 Central Park South
  - Cahn, Leopold Mrs. (Offsite-box 35, Folder 747)
    Hartsdale, NY
  - Campbell, Heyworth, 1935 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 59)
    325 East 72nd Street
  - Campbell, J. W., Mrs., undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 60)
    Briarcliff Manor, NY
  - Carney, Don, 1934 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 61)
    300 Central Park West, El Dorado Apartments
  - Carney, Matthew J., 1929 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 62)
  - Carpenter, Arthur S. (Offsite-box 35, Folder 748)
    Rome, NY
  - Carroll Liquor Store, 1933-1934 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 63)
    269 Madison Avenue
  - Cary, Melbert B., Jr., undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 64)
    Millbrook, NY
  - Cawen, Arthur, 1937 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 65)
    39 East 74th Street
  - Celanese Corp., 1934 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 66)
    180 Madison Avenue
  - Chambers, 1942 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 67)
    Riverdale, Bronx, NY
  - Charak Furniture Company, 1935 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 68)
    444 Madison Avenue
  - Charles of London, 1931-1937 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 69)
    Grand Central Palace (exhibition)
    See also: Series II, Box 25, Folder 669
  - Charles Roberson of London, 1930-1933 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 70)
    See also: Series II, Box 25, Folder 670
  - Chase, Harry Woodburn, Chancellor of NYU, 1933 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 71)
    2 Fifth Avenue
  - Cheney, Ward, Mrs., 1931 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 72)
  - Chesapeake House, 1944 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 73)
    Madison Avenue and 34th Street
    See also: Series II, Box 25, Folder 671
  - Christ Church (Offsite-box 36, Folder 749)
    Rye, NY
  - Christian Science Church (Offsite-box 36, Folder 750)
    Pleasantvile, NY
  - City Housing Corp., 1928 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 74)
    Sunnyside, Queens
  - Clemens, James B., Mrs., 1934 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 75)
    960 Fifth Avenue
  - Cleveland and Randall, 1932 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 76)
    447 East 57th Street
  - Cogswell, Ledyard, Jr., 1932 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 77)
    Loudenville, NY
  - Chen, I. M., 1942 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 78)
    1100 Park Avenue
  - Cole, Philip G., Dr., 1932-1933 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 79-82)
    Irvington-on-Hudson, NY
  - Coleman, Townsend P., 1928 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 83)
    1235 Park Avenue
  - Collins, Kenneth, 1931 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 84)
    455 West 23rd Street, London Terrace
  - Condict, Philip K. (Offsite-box 36, Folder 751)
  - Cortile Restaurant, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 85)
    36 West 44th Street
    See also: Series II, Box 25, Folder 672
  - Cottier, A.E. (Offsite-box 36, Folder 752)
    Scarsdale, NY
  - Coulters, Charles Mrs. (Offsite-box 36, Folder 753)
    Tuxedo, NY
  - Court House Club, 1930 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 86)
    206 East 65th Street
  - Cracken, Frank L., Mrs., 1922 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 87)
    123 East 73rd Street
  - Crisp, Arthur, Mrs., 1935 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 88)
    248 Lexington Avenue
  - Cross, Wellington, Mrs., 1933 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 89)
    155 East 47th Street
  - Cudahy, Misses, 1926 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 90)
    907 Fifth Avenue
  - Cullman, Howard (Offsite-box 36, Folder 754)
    "Woodbrook Farm", Purchase, NY
  - Cullman, Howard S., 1941 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 91)
    480 Park Avenue
  - Cumming, Eileen, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 92)
  - Cumming, Rose, 1921-1923 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 93)
    561 Madison Avenue
  - Cumming, Rose, 1927 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 94)
    54 East 55th Street
  - Cumming, Rose, 1931 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 95)
    489 Park Avenue
  - Cummings, A. D., Mrs., 1921 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 96)
    18 East 47th Street
  - Curry, H. Douglas, 1925-1934 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 97-98)
    5 East 57th Street
  - Curtis, A. H., Mrs., 1926 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 99)
    125 East 70th Street
  - Danby Company Inc., 1933 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 100)
    227 East 47th Street
  - Daniel H. Farr Company, 1930 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 101)
    11 East 74th Street
  - Dater, Alfred W. (Offsite-box 36, Folder 755)
    Fisher's Island, NY
  - David Mannes School, 1923 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 102)
    157 East 74th Street
  - Davis, George P., Mrs., 1930 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 103)
    375 Park Avenue
  - Davis, Tobe Collier, Mrs., 1934 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 104)
    169 East 78th Street
  - Delafield, Edward (Offsite-box 36, Folder 756)
  - Delafield, F. P., 1927 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 105)
    121 East 74th Street
  - Davie, Preston Mrs. (Offsite-box 36, Folder 757)
  - Dent, H. C., 1928 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 106)
    Bootle Avenue, Englewood, NJ